Speaker: We all know that too much sugar and salt isn’t good for us.
But do we really know how much sugar and salt are in some of the things we eat and drink every day?
Let’s start with sugar.
According to the American Heart Association, the maximum healthy limit for a woman is twenty-four grams of sugar a day.
That’s just six teaspoons.
For a man it is no more than thirty-six grams, which is nine teaspoons.
Here we have an egg, a can of coke, a small bar of dark chocolate, and an apple.
How much sugar do you think they contain?
One of them has thirty-five grams of sugar.
That’s eleven grams more than the healthy limit for a woman in a day.
Which one do you think it is?
Yes, it’s the can of coke. A can of Coke has approximately thirty-five grams of sugar. That is a lot.
And which has no sugar at all?
Of course, it’s the egg.
So what about the other two?
Which do you think has more sugar, the chocolate or the apple?
Surprisingly, it’s the apple.
The apple has approximately twenty-three grams of sugar. That’s quite a lot.
But it’s fructose, a natural sugar. And remember that fruit is also good for you, as it contains vitamin C.
The chocolate bar only has a little sugar, just ten grams.
But remember, it’s dark chocolate, and it’s only a small bar.
What about salt? How much salt can we eat in a day?
This time it’s the same for men and women.
The answer is no more than six grams.
Here we have a small packet of crisps, a bottle of olive oil, a bottle of mineral water and a piece of bread.
So how much salt do they contain? Which one has a lot of salt, and which one has none?
You may be surprised to hear that the one with a lot of salt is the piece of white bread.
It has approximately nought point five grams.
And which one has no salt at all?
No, it’s not the mineral water, it’s the olive oil.
It contains no salt at all, and as part of a Mediterranean diet, it’s very healthy.
So what about the other two.
Well, a small packet of crisps has approximately nought point three four grams of salt.
And lastly, there is a little salt in the mineral water. Just nought point nought nought two three grams.
So when you’re shopping, how do you know what to buy to make sure it doesn’t have too much sugar or salt?
The answer is, always check the list of ingredients, and remember what your daily limit is.